Inventory of the Edward J. Rozek papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 2015 Incremental Materials, 1939-2004 (Boxes 131-148)
  - Teaching materials, 1940-2004
    - Korea, North and South, 1976-2003 (Box-folder 135: 11)
    - Lenin, Vladimir, undated (Box-folder 135: 12)
    - Liberalism/Leftism, 2004 (Box-folder 135: 13)
    - Maps, 1940-1982 (Box-folder 135: 14)
    - Maps, 1940-1982 (Box-folder 136: 1)
    - Marxism, 1963-1983 (Box-folder 136: 2)
    - Middle East, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 136: 3)
    - Miscellaneous teaching materials and clippings, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 136: 4)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1988-1998 (Box-folder 136: 5)
    - Nazism, undated (Box-folder 136: 6)
    - Nuclear weapons, 2000 (Box-folder 136: 7)
    - Philosophy, 1978-2002 (Box-folder 136: 8)
    - Poland, 1942-2003 (Box-folder 136: 9)
    - Political spectrum, undated (Box-folder 136: 10)
    - Potsdam Conference, undated (Box-folder 137: 1)
    - Putin, Vladimir, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 137: 2)
    - Radio Free Europe, undated (Box-folder 137: 3)
    - Radio Free Europe memoranda, 1954 (Box-folder 137: 4)
    - Reagan, Ronald, 1968 (Box-folder 137: 5)
    - Red Peasant International, undated (Box-folder 137: 6)
    - Romania, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 137: 7)
    - Rome, undated (Box-folder 137: 8)
    - Russian Revolution of 1917, undated (Box-folder 137: 9)
    - Russia, undated (Box-folder 137: 10-11)
    - Russian attempted coup of 1993, undated (Box-folder 137: 12)
    - Russian post-communist era, 1999-2003 (Box-folder 137: 13)
    - Socialism, undated (Box-folder 137: 14)
    - Sakharov, Andrei, 1986 (Box-folder 137: 15)
    - Scott, James F., 1974 (Box-folder 137: 16)
    - Soviet Union, 1992 (Box-folder 137: 17)
    - Soviet Union, 1944-2003 (Box-folder 138: 1-4)
    - Soviet Union clippings, 1947-1968 (Box-folder 138: 5)
    - Stalin, Joseph, undated (Box-folder 138: 3)
    - Syllabi, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 138: 4)
    - Taiwan, 1988-2000 (Box-folder 138: 5)
    - Tehran, undated (Box-folder 138: 6)
    - Thieme, Frederick P., 1975 (Box-folder 138: 7)
    - Ukraine, undated (Box-folder 139: 1)
    - United States, 2000 (Box-folder 139: 2)
    - United States defense and military, 1983-2003 (Box-folder 139: 3-7)
    - United States 20th century, 1954-1995 (Box-folder 139: 8)
    - United States 21st century, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 139: 9)
    - Vietnam and South East Asia, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 140: 1)
    - Volker Fund, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 140: 2)
    - World affairs, 1951 (Box-folder 140: 3)
    - World Today, 1957 (Box-folder 140: 4)
    - World War II, 1987 (Box-folder 140: 5)
    - Yalta Conference, 1985 (Box-folder 140: 6)
    - Yugoslavia, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 140: 7)
  - Personal files, 1939-1982 (Boxes 140-146)
    Notes, correspondence, quotations, articles, clippings, and student records.
    - Polish manuscript for Rozek's book Allied Wartime Diplomacy: A Pattern in Poland, undated (Box-folder 140: 8-11)
    - Quotations and notes, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 141: 1-2)
    - Clippings, 1951-1982 (Box-folder 141: 3)
    - Articles regarding Communism, Marxism, and the Soviet Union, 1940-1965 (Box-folder 141: 4-7)
    - Articles regarding foreign policy, 1939-1949 (Box-folder 141: 8)
    - Articles regarding foreign policy, 1939-1949 (Box-folder 142: 1)
    - Notes and articles regarding Capitalism and the United States, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 142: 2)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 142: 3)
    - Republican National Convention Telephone Directory and Guide, 1976 (Box-folder 142: 4)
    - Radio Free Europe materials, 1955 (Box-folder 142: 5)
    - "Development of Constitutionalism" by Edward Rozek, undated (Box-folder 142: 6)
    - Teaching records from Colorado University, 1960 (Box-folder 142: 7)
    - Edward Rozek's student records, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 142: 8)
    - The Colorado Quarterly journal, 1958 (Box-folder 142: 9)
    - Survey journal, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 142: 10-11)
    - Political pamphlets, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 143: 1)
    - Transcript of the meeting of the Committee of Review of the Senate of the University of Colorado regarding Edward J. Rozek, 1964 (Box-folder 143: 2)
    - General correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 143: 3-5)
    - Maddock, Charles S., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 143: 6)
    - Chronological clippings and correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 143: 7-9)
    - Chronological clippings and correspondence, 1978- (Box-folder 144: 1-16)
    - Index cards and notes with inspirational quotes, undated (Box-folder 144: 17-25)
    - Index cards and notes with inspirational quotes, undated (Box-folder 145: 1-8)
    - Index cards and notes with inspirational quotes, undated (Box-folder 146: 1-6)
  - Polish materials, 1945-1995 (Boxes 146-148)
    Printed matter, memoranda, clippings, and article regarding Poland. Mainly in Polish.
    - NSZZ Solidarnosc materials, 1981-1995 (Box-folder 146: 7)
    - Clippings from Time Magazine, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 146: 8)
    - Map of France, undated (Box-folder 146: 9)
    - Press releases and speeches from the Polish government, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 146: 10)
    - Printed matter regarding Poland, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 147: 1)
    - Scholarly articles regarding Poland, 1954-1961 (Box-folder 147: 2)
    - "Communization of Poland: Falsification of 1947 Elections,", 1954 (Box-folder 147: 3-5)
    - Article manuscript regarding Soviet-Polish wartime relations., undated (Box-folder 147: 6)
    - Polish National Council, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 147: 7)
    - Światło newsletter, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 147: 8)
    - Ks. Henryk Jankowski: Szkic biograficzny newsletter, 1992 (Box-folder 147: 9)
    - "Sprawozdanie Stenograficzne: z 21-22 posiedzenia Sejmu Polskiej Rzeczypospolitej Ludowej,", 1958 (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - Ku Nowej Polsce, 1945 (Box-folder 148: 2)
    - "Nasza Myśl miesięcznik oficerski 8,", 1947 (Box-folder 148: 3)
    - Newsletters from Poland, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 148: 4)
    - "Narόd polski w walce o woność i niepodległość,", 1957 (Box-folder 148: 5)
    - Wolnosc i Niezawislosc materials, 1951 (Box-folder 148: 6)
      Materials from the Freedom and Independence organization.
  - Sound recordings (Boxes 149-151)
    See Sound Recordings series for further description.